DAVID BARON

Toronto, ON

Phone: (905) 999-0683 | Email: dcpb777@gmail.com LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/david-baron-714370226/

GitHub: github.com/HORSESH0E

Portfolio: https://github.com/HORSESH0E/DavidsPortfolioRepo

SUMMARY

Web Developer with background in scientific data collection and technical installation. Committed to accuracy and detail. As both a manager and technician, practiced process implementation, development, documentation, and been responsible for training and evaluation. Experienced in prioritizing tasks and communicating salient information accommodating multiple perspectives and initiating innovative progression, and recently earned a Certificate in Full Stack Web Development from the University of Toronto.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Front-End: HTML5, CSS, Bootstrap, JavaScript, jQuery, AJAX, ReactJS, Handlebars.js

Back-End: Node.js, Express.js, MySQL, Sequelize ORM, MongoDB, Mongoose ODM, Insomnia

Concepts: APIs, REST, MVC, TDD, JSON, XML

Tools: Git, Github, GitLab, Firebase, Heroku, JawsDB, VS Code5

Certifications: Site Master Line Sweep Certification - Anritsu, The Art of Encouragement - Ontario Society of

Adlerian Psychology

PROJECTS

Movie Music Magic | https://github.com/HORSESH0E/movieMusicMagic | https://hOrsesh0e.github.io/movieMusicMagic/

- Helps users avoid distractions when they wish to find high-quality and moving music appropriate for study, meditation or work.
- Built and maintained team morale through conceptual development to project completion. Consulted with each team member and coded in every area of the project
- Git, GitHub, Trello, Slack, JavaScript, CSS, HTML

Glide | https://github.com/HORSESH0E/glide-activity-carpooling | https://glide-activity-carpooling.herokuapp.com/

- Connects users of similar interests with each other so they can enjoy distant activities for a fraction of the travel costs
- Lead the team through brainstorming and worked on every aspect of the project to bring it to completion
- Git, GitHub, Node.js, Express.js, Express-Session, Sequelize, Sequelize-Connect-Session, MySQL2, Dotenv, Bcrypt, JawsDB Add-On, @Faker, Trello, Slack, JavaScript, CSS, HTML

EXPERIENCE

Property Development - Self-Employed DBR Development

2021 – present Arden, ON

Designing and building remote recreation properties providing families with a turn-key nature-adventure experience that is unforgettable for children and an actual vacation for parents. Utilizing experience in hospitality, real estate, teaching, carpentry and design.

Key Accomplishments:

• Located real-estate, negotiated purchase, found training, acquired licenses/permits, sourced vehicles, provisioned materials, equipment and supplies: project cost \$45,000.

- Created and implemented the custom construction processes required for material handling and fabrication on-site.
- In one season, single-handedly cleared land, erected a large material/work shelter, purpose-built a large dock, and two-storey bunkie on a water-access-only property.

Renovation / Handyman Carpenter - Self-Employed Handyman Solutions

2011 - 2019

Toronto, ON

Consulted with clients, prepared estimates, sourced materials and completed various projects involving concrete work, rough carpentry, roofing, plumbing, electrical, HVAC, dry wall, finish carpentry. Utilized communication, negotiation, critical thinking and persuasive skills to build trust and rapport with clients providing safe and cost-effective solutions.

Key Accomplishments:

• Built a business based entirely on word-of-mouth by under-promising and over delivering leveraging my attention to detail..

Real Estate Salesperson - Employee

2016 - 2018

ReMax West

Klienberg, ON

Determined cold-calling, neighborhood door-knocking and consistent hosting of Open Houses generated significant business in just my first season.

Key Accomplishments:

- Delivered full support to my clients throughout the process from obtaining financing, considering prospects and ensuring their property was ready for closing.
- Utilized the latest technology from drone footage to social media to provide actionable information that enticed prospective buyers from more than 4 hours away.

Math Tutor - Self-Employed

2011 - 2016

Toronto, ON

Evaluated student's aptitude and performance to prepare specialized lesson plans and activities for primary level students in Math.

Key Accomplishments:

Wesbell

• Encouraged can-do attitudes in students with motivational deficits bringing one student from a failing grade to an enthusiastic and successful member of the school's math club.

Telecommunications Contractor/ Installer / Power Technician - Employee

2008 - 2011

Mississauga, ON

Responsible for telecom equipment installation according to client specifications in a collaborative setting, quality assurance and control, reporting of site status and on-going refinement of installation process. Key Accomplishments:

- With no formal training, recognized for my high quality of complex installations, surpassing client requirements within tight timelines
- For Ericsson/DAVE Wireless, formulated SOP document for labeling and information tracking on all installations the SOP was adopted by all other service providers.
- (DAVE became Wind Mobile.)

Board Member - Volunteer

2008 - 2009

Scarborough Music Theatre

Scarborough, ON

Responsible for branding, marketing material design, re-design and maintenance of website and ticketing research essential to the business of the overall company and its three affiliated theatre groups. Key Accomplishments:

- Received the groups' 'Randy Leslie' award for making an outstanding contribution to the company.
- Modernized the website through self-directed learning of Adobe Dreamweaver 3, raised traffic more than 300%, attained third position in Google search, previously ranked 70th.

• Investigated various ticketing companies, interviewed different service providers and their existing clients. Recommend the ticketing agent ultimately chosen.

EDUCATION

Full Stack Boot Camp Certificate: University of Toronto, Toronto, ON

Degree or Certification: School, City, ST

Registered Real Estate Representative: OREA, Vaughan, ON

Certificate of Qualification & Registration: Ontario College of Teachers, Toronto, ON

Primary / Junior Education Program: Canisius College, Buffalo, NY

Diploma in Culinary Management: Sir Sandford Fleming College, Peterborough, ON

Bachelor of Arts – Humanities: York University, Toronto, ON